<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian on Not Much of a Blog</title>
    <link>https://tkngch.github.io/tags/bayesian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bayesian on Not Much of a Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Takao Noguchi. Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://tkngch.github.io/tags/bayesian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Bayes</title>
      <link>https://tkngch.github.io/post/2016-12-26_hierarchical-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tkngch.github.io/post/2016-12-26_hierarchical-bayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, data contain multiple entries from observation units. For example,
researchers may be interested in effectiveness of medical treatments, and
tested several treatments in several different cities. Then, it may make sense
to consider that the effectiveness may be overall consistent across cities but
slightly vary between the cities, as population characteristic may vary between
the cities. For instance, one city may have more younger people than another.
In these cases, hierarchical Bayes may help. In this blog post, I review
hierarchical Bayes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dirichlet process mixture model as a cognitive model of category learning</title>
      <link>https://tkngch.github.io/post/2016-12-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 15:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tkngch.github.io/post/2016-12-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In cognitive science/psychology, Dirichlet process mixture model (DPMM) is
considered as a rational model of category learning (Anderson, 1991; Sanborn,
Griffiths &amp;amp; Navarro, 2010). That is, the DPMM is used to approximate how human
learns to categorise objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I review the DPMM, assuming that all the features are discrete.
The implementation in C++ can be found
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tkngch/dirichlet-process-mixture-model&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>